Cinthia Fontoura de Souza

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Brazilian | Dublin 9 | cinthiafontouras@gmail.com +353 83 385 9229 | <u>Portfolio</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Junior Software Developer enrolled in a Full Stack software development program at Code Institute, where I am learning HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. In addition, I am studying Agile Methodology, UX/UI, SEO and Web Accessibility. I am actively seeking career change opportunities as a junior software developer. Working 13 years as a Chef, I had the chance to develop my teamwork skills in restaurants where I trained people, managed small teams and worked on my own when I ran my bakery.

KEY SKILLS

• Languages: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Python

Databases: MongoDB
Libraries: JQuery
Version Control: Git, GitHub
Frameworks: Bootstrap, Flask

Others: VS Code, Gitpod, Node.js, Linux, npm
Design: Figma, Design Thinking, UX/UI principles

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Jan 2022 - Feb 2023 Code Institute

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Credit Rated by The University of the West of Scotland

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021 Ibat College Dublin

Professional Diploma in UX/UI Design

Distinction grade received

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

- 1. Restaurant 104 | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Hosting Ireland/cPanel.
- 2. Rock Paper Scissors Game | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, Python, Gitpod, Heroku.
- 3. JavaScript Quiz | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Gitpod, GitHub Pages.
- 4. Portfolio | Live site | GitHub | Figma, HTML, CSS, Git, Netlify.

COLLABORATIVE PROJECTS

- Emojourney | <u>Live site</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | Agile Methodology, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, GitHub Pages.
- 2. Terra Matter | Live site | GitHub | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, GitHub Pages.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023 Version 1, Dublin, Ireland

Associate Consultant

• Digital Skills Academy.

Nov 2021 - Present Richmond Restaurant, Dublin, Ireland

Chef de Partie

- Michelin Bib Gourmand Restaurant since 2018.
- Plating meals and desserts.
- Preparation following the HACCP.

May 2021 - Present Restaurant 104, Dublin, Ireland

Web Designer

- Design, develop and maintain their website.
- HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Git, cPanel.

Dec 2020 - Nov 2021 Chef de Partie

- Fill up the HACCP control sheets.
- · Control and organisation of kitchen stock.
- Preparation and plating meals and desserts.

CERTIFICATES AND COURSES

- CISCO Cybersecurity Essentials
- Technical Support Fundamentals (20 hours)
- The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking (25 hours)
- HTML and CSS (66 hours)
- Web Accessibility (20 hours)
- Programmer beginner (79 hours)
- Agility: Driving Agile Transformation (6 hours)
- SEO: website optimisation (8 hours)
- Google Analytics 4: Implementation and Reporting (10 hours)
- Computer Architecture: Behind How Your Program Works (8 hours)
- HTTP: Understanding the web behind the scenes (14 hours)
- Style Guide: Assembling Pages with Components (8 hours)
- Linux I: knowing and using the terminal (4 hours)
- Git and GitHub: Control and Share Your Code (6 hours)
- Design Thinking: enabling solutions (8 hours)
- Figma: Visual design of a mobile site (10 hours)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Stamp 4 (family member) visa.
- Portuguese (Native), English (Intermediate).
- 1st Place in the Code Institute's World Emoji Day Hackathon, July 2022.

References Upon Request